<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on chrmod.net</title>
    <link>https://chrmod.net/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on chrmod.net</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 May 2016 18:13:33 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://chrmod.net/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>hello world</title>
      <link>https://chrmod.net/post/hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2016 18:13:33 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrmod.net/post/hello-world/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Will try to go fast with this one as it&amp;rsquo;s my first blog post ever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;hello-world:aa77bbfd89a7b0ff10def205b9c08d51&#34;&gt;Hello World!&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Guess that&amp;rsquo;s the phrase, that most developers use when they start a new project, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;yet-another-dev-blog:aa77bbfd89a7b0ff10def205b9c08d51&#34;&gt;Yet another dev blog&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, chrmod.net is going to be yet another blog by some kind of developer. You can expect to find here code/configuration snippets, tips for my favorite tools, or solutions to tech problems that I found surprising.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really wanted to start writing for quite some time now, but you know how it is, beginnings are hard. But finally something has changed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;trigger:aa77bbfd89a7b0ff10def205b9c08d51&#34;&gt;Trigger&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a very simple thing that I wanted to do (it often starts like that) - to post a picture online, so other people can see how my linux destkop environment looks like atm. Easy you would think, well, sure it is simple for some, not for me.. I&amp;rsquo;ve got an image, a place to post it (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/unixporn&#34;&gt;unixporn&lt;/a&gt; subreddit), and there was only one problem, reddit is not hosting images - it wants an URL.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OK. There are many free image hosting, most people on unixporn use imgur.com, but that would be too easy.
Instead I decided to finally kick off own website in a form of a blog. After 24 hours, here we are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;technology:aa77bbfd89a7b0ff10def205b9c08d51&#34;&gt;Technology&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This would not be a tech blog if I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t explain what, how and why I did it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;requirements:aa77bbfd89a7b0ff10def205b9c08d51&#34;&gt;Requirements&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all, I didn&amp;rsquo;t really want to pay for anything (at least not in the beginning). chrmod.net is suppose to be a blog for sharing stuff, not earning money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, with traditional approach (which I assume is wordpress + mysql + apache, etc), there is so much stuff to care about and to maintain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Third, I do like to write code and tend to avoid CMSs as much as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;solution:aa77bbfd89a7b0ff10def205b9c08d51&#34;&gt;Solution&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The obvious way to go was to use some kind of static page generator and host it on github as apparently we&amp;rsquo;re able to use for free for personal stuff (citing chastell on &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/chastell/status/736926755999617024&#34;&gt;this one&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also I really wanted to host my stuff over https. I knew there is letsencrypt, but to use it with github pages didn&amp;rsquo;t look that easy or even possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fortunately I found kludsec that not only provide a free CDN but they also issued SSL certificate from letsencrypt automatically! Amazing!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Summarizing the setup is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;hosting: &lt;a href=&#34;https://pages.github.com/&#34;&gt;github pages&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CDN: &lt;a href=&#34;https://kloudsec.com/&#34;&gt;kludsec&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SSL: &lt;a href=&#34;https://letsencrypt.org/&#34;&gt;letsencrypt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;engine: &lt;a href=&#34;http://gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;hugo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ending-note:aa77bbfd89a7b0ff10def205b9c08d51&#34;&gt;Ending note&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is that damned screenshot which started all this mess:&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://chrmod.net/hello-world/desktop-screenshot-2016-05-29.png&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;gruvbox theme for i3wm, vim and tmux&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;What is on it, is a topic for another post!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>